Guide to the Rufus King Papers, 1766-1899, (bulk, 1783-1826) MS 1660
New-York Historical Society
Rufus King papers
1766-1899 (Bulk 1783-1826)
New-York Historical Society
King, Rufus, 1755-1827
MS 1660
17.5 Linear feet (40 boxes and 66 volumes)
The collection contains the papers documenting the political career and private interests of Federalist statesman Rufus King. The collection includes official and private correspondence with other political figures in the early history of the United States, letterbooks, account books, notebooks, financial documents, diaries, memoranda, and essays.
Access Restrictions
This collection may be stored offsite. To arrange to consult it, please go to www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.
Portions of the collection that have been microfilmed will be brought to researchers in that format and can be made available via interlibrary loan.
Arrangement
The material is loosely arranged by format and then chronologically. Most of the correspondence is numbered and the numbers generally correspond to the chronological order. Most of the undated items are unnumbered. Much of the material has been item level catalogued.
The material in a envelope previously listed as "Misc. Mss." is now in box 90. Material previously listed in "Box A' is now boxes 24, 26, 27. Contact the manuscript reference desk for more information.
Microfilm: Material in boxes and volumes 24, 26, 28, 31, 46-48, 51-54, 56, 58, 59-62, 73, 81, and 87 is on microfilm.
Chronology
1755 March 24
Rufus King born in Scarborough, Maine, then a section of Massachusetts, the eldest son of farmer-merchant Richard and Isabella King.
1777
Graduates from Harvard.
1778
Serves as an aide to General Sullivan during the unsuccessful expedition to Rhode Island. He is honorably discharged.
1780
After studying law at Newburyport, Massachusetts, under Theophilus Parsons, King is admitted to the bar and opens up a practice Newburyport.
1783-1785
Serves as a delegate to the Massachusetts General Court.
1784-1786
Elected as a delegate to Congress from Trenton, New Jersey. King urges for a resolution against the expansion of slavery into the Northwest Territory and presses for all states to financially contribute to a national government.
1786 March 30
Marries Mary Alsop, daughter of John Alsop, a New York merchant and fellow member of the Continental Congress.
1787
King represents Massachusetts in the Constitutional Convention. He attends the convention unconvinced that the Articles of Confederation, which advocated states' rights, needed to be altered. He leaves the convention an advocate for change to a powerful central government. King works on the final draft of the Constitution and is one of its signers.
1788
King leaves his law practice in Massachusetts to move to New York.
1789
Elected to the New York Assembly and chosen to be a United States senator with Philip Schuyler.
1791
Elected as a Director for the Bank of the United States.
1794
Siding with the Federalists, King supports the Jay Treaty between Great Britain and the United States. With Alexander Hamilton and John Jay, he publishes a series of letters detailing the treaty under the pseudonym "Camillus."
1795
Reelected to the US Senate.
1796-1803
During his second term in the Senate, King is appointed by George Washington to succeed Thomas Pinckney as Minister Plenipotentiary to Great Britain.
1804
King is nominated to be the Federalist candidate for vice-president, with Charles C. Pinckney as the presidential candidate. After the candidates lose to Thomas Jefferson and George Clinton, King retreats to his estate, King Manor, in Jamaica, Long Island.
1808
King and Pinckney are again nominated as Federalist candidates and lose to James Madison and George Clinton.
1813
King elected again to be a United States senator from New York. Although he was originally opposed to the War of 1812, he becomes a supporter after the British attack on Washington.
1816
Runs for President as the Federalist candidate and loses to James Monroe. King leads opposition in the Senate against the establishment of the Second Bank of the United States.
1818
Author of Navigation Act of 1818.
1820
Reelected by the New York legislature as United States Senator from New York. While in the Senate, he opposes the extension of slavery and the Missouri Compromise.
1825
King retires from the Senate due to ill heath. With the persuasion of President John Quincy Adams, he returns to England for another position as Minister to Great Britain.
1826
King falls ill again and returns to America.
1827 April 29
Dies at the age of 72 and is buried in the cemetery of Grace Church in Jamaica, Long Island. He is survived by his children John Alsop, Charles, James Gore, Edward, Frederic Gore.
For further information see:
Brush, Edward Hale, Rufus King and His Times. New York: Nicholas Brown, 1926.
Ernst, Robert, Rufus King: American Federalist. Chapel Hill: University of North Carolina Press, 1968.
Provenance
Donation by Mrs. Charles R. King, 1902. Supplemental material (Volumes 93-103), 1979.
Related Material at The New-York Historical Society
Additional material related to Rufus King can be found in the King Family Papers and the Erving-King Family Papers at the New-York Historical Society.
Much of this material can also be found in the six volume, The Life and Correspondence of Rufus King, Comprising his Letters, Private and Official, his Public Documents and his Speeches, edited by his grandson, Charles R. King.
Transcriptions of the notes of Rufus King in the Federal Convention of 1787 can be found at the website of the Avalon Project of Yale University Law School.
Scope and Content Note
The Rufus King collection documents the career of Federalist Rufus King as a New York Assemblyman, U.S. Senator, US Minister to Great Britain, Federalist party leader, and candidate for Presidency and Vice-Presidency. Although the bulk of the collection is official and private correspondence, it also consists of notes, memoranda, diaries, essays, account books, newspaper articles, and a few legal documents. The collection also has the notes and letters dated from 1894-1899 of Charles R. King, Rufus King's grandson, who edited his grandfather's papers for the six volume The Life and Correspondence of Rufus King. Many of Rufus King's notebooks include later memoranda from Charles R. King commenting on the text.
The collection principally covers eighteenth and early nineteenth century politics in early America and England. Specific topics documented include the Constitutional Convention of 1787, King's opposition to the War of 1812, the Navigation Act of 1818, the Missouri Compromise, and the administration and sale of public lands. It also describes negotiations between the United States and Great Britain over the Jay Treaty, Barbary affairs, South American independence, the East India Trade, the Fugitive Slave Acts, and the British-French negotiations in 1803.
A large amount of material is correspondence with American political figures such as John Adams, John Quincy Adams, Alexander Hamilton, William Hindman, Charles Jared Ingersoll, John Jay, John Alsop King, Charles King, Nicholas Low, James Madison, Gouverneur Morris, Timothy Pickering, Thomas Pinkney, Granville Sharp, John Trumbull, George Washington, and Noah Webster. Others represented in the correspondence include Francisco de Miranda, Joseph Pitcairn, John Alsop, Juan Pablo Viscardo y Guzman, George Canning, and Henry Clay. The collection also contains documents and correspondence of family members Richard King, John A. King, and Charles King.
The personal material of Rufus King includes his correspondence, household account books, a 1802 diary kept while traveling in Europe, and an inventory of his library. It also consists of notebooks, diaries, and essays containing King's observations on his contemporaries and domestic and foreign politics. Some of his notebooks include extracts from books read by King along with his own comments and observations.
This collection supports research on the nuances of King's lengthy political career as well as the early political history of the United States.
Abstracts (summaries); Account books.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Diaries.; Essays.; Anglo-French War, 1793-1802.; Constitutional history -- New York (State); Diplomatic and consular service, American.; Diplomats.; Finance, Personal.; Presidential candidates -- United States.; Public land sales -- United States.; Statesmen.; Vice-Presidential candidates -- United States.; New York (State) -- Politics and government -- 1775-1865.; South America -- History -- Wars of Independence, 1806-1830.; United States -- Economic conditions -- To 1865.; United States -- Foreign relations -- 1783-1865.; United States -- Foreign relations -- Treaties.; United States -- History -- Tripolitan War, 1801-1805.; United States -- History -- War of 1812.; United States -- Politics and government -- 1783-1865.; Letter books.; Memorandums.; Notebooks.; Receipts (financial records); Treaty of Amity, Commerce, and Navigation, with the United States of America (1794 November 19); Adams, John, 1735-1826; Adams, John Quincy, 1767-1848; Ames, Fisher, 1758-1808; Baring, Francis, Sir, 1740-1810; Bentinck, William Henry Cavendish, Lord, 1774-1839; Cabot, George, 1752-1823; Gerry, Elbridge, 1744-1814; Gore, Christopher, 1758-1827; Grenville, William Wyndham Grenville, Baron, 1759-1834; Hamilton, Alexander, 1757-1804; Hindman, William, 1743-1822; Ingersoll, Charles Jared, 1782-1862; Jay, John, 1745-1829; King, Charles, 1789-1867; King, John Alsop, 1788-1867; Low, Nicholas, 1739-1826; Madison, James, 1751-1836; Morris, Gouverneur, 1752-1816; Pickering, Timothy, 1745-1829; Pinckney, Thomas, 1750-1828; Schuyler, Philip John, 1733-1804; Sedgwick, Theodore, 1746-1813; Sharp, Granville, 1735-1813; Troup, Robert, 1757-1832; Trumbull, John, 1750-1831; Vansittart, Nicholas, 1766-1851; Washington, George, 1732-1799; Webster, Noah, 1758-1843; Wilberforce, William, 1759-1833; Wolcott, Oliver, 1760-1833; Baring Brothers and Co.; Bird, Savage, & Bird (London, England); Federal Party (U.S.); United States. Constitutional Convention (1787)
- Box 1- Rufus King Correspondence/Convention Notes
  - Letters to and from Rufus King/Convention Notes, 1785 Mar.-1785 May (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King/Convention Notes, 1785 June-1785 Dec (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King/Convention Notes, 1786 Jan.-1786 April (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King/Convention Notes, 1786 May-1786 Oct. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King/Convention Notes, 1786 Nov.-1787 July (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King/Convention Notes, 1787 Aug.-1787 Dec. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Letter from Rufus King to Joshua Coit, Newbury, Massachusetts, Dec. 14, 1778 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Box 2- Notes and Articles
  - Notes and Articles, including "First Report of the Committee of the Whole Convention- 1787" (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Notes and Articles, 1785 June-1887 July (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Box 3- Rufus King Correspondence
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1788 Jan.-1788 June (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1788 July-1788 Dec. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1789 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, [1790] (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1790 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1791 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1792 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Box 4- Rufus King Correspondence
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, Other Notes, [1793] (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1793 Jan.-1793 Nov. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1793 Dec. (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Box 5- Rufus King Correspondence
  - Various Notes, includes notes on Albert Gallatin, [1794] (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1794 Jan. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 1794 Letterbook, 1794 Feb.- 1794 May (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1794 Feb.-1794 Mar. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1794 Apr.-1794 June (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1794 July-1794 Sept. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1794 Oct.-1794 Dec. (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Box 6- Rufus King Correspondence
  - Various Notes, [1795] (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1795 Jan.-1795 Apr. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1795 June-1795 Dec. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Notes on Seizures of Shipping on High Seas, excerpts from Commercial Treaty between France and England, [1796] (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1796 Jan.-1796 June (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1796 July-1796 Dec. (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Box 7- Rufus King Correspondence
  - Various Notes, [1797] (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1797 Jan.-1797 June (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1797 July-1797 Dec. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1798 Jan.-1798 June (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1798 July-1798 Aug. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1798 Sept.-1798 Dec. (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Box 8- Rufus King Correspondence
  - Various Notes, [1799] (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1799 Jan.-1799 May (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Letterbook, 1799 Mar.-1799 Dec. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1799 June-1799 Dec. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1800 Jan.-1800 June (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1800 July-1800 Dec. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1801 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Various Notes, 1802 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1802 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Box 9- Rufus King Correspondence
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1803 Jan.-1803 Apr. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1803 May 1-1803 May 14 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1803 May 15-1803 May 30 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1803 June-1803 July (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1803 Aug.-1803 Oct. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1803 Nov.-1803 Dec. (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Box 10- Rufus King Correspondence
  - Various Notes, [1804] (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1804 Jan.-1804 Mar. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1804 Apr.-1804 June (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1804 July-1804 Dec. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1805 Jan.-1805 Mar. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1805 Apr.-1805 Aug. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1805 Sept.-1805 Dec. (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Box 11- Rufus King Correspondence
  - Various Notes, [1806] (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1806 Jan.-1806 Feb. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1806 Mar.-1806 June (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1806 July-1806 Dec. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1807 Jan.-1807 Apr. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1807 May-1807 June (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1807 July-1807 Dec. (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Box 12- Rufus King Correspondence
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1808 Jan.-1808 Mar. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1808 Apr.-1808 Aug. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1808 Sept.-1808 Dec. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, [1809] (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1809 Jan.-1809 Mar. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1809 Apr.-1809 July (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1809 Aug.-1809 Dec. (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Box 13- Rufus King Correspondence
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1810 Jan.-1810 Feb. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1810 Mar.-1810 Dec. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, [1811] (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1811 Jan.-1811 July (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1811 Aug.-1811 Dec. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, [1812] (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1812 Jan.-1812 June (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1812 July-1812 Dec. (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, [1813] (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1813 (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Box 14- Rufus King Correspondence
  - Notes of Speeches and Debates on Bank of US, [1814-1818] (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, [1814] (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1814 Jan.-1814 Feb. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1814 Mar.-1814 June (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1814 July-1814 Dec. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, [1815] (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1815 Jan.-1815 Apr. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1815 May-1815 Dec. (Box 14, Folder 8)
- Box 15- Rufus King Correspondence
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, [1816] (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1816 Jan.-1816 Feb. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1816 Mar.-1816 Apr. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1816 May-1816 July (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1816 Aug.-1816 Dec. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Notes, "1817 Almanack" (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1817 Jan.-1817 Apr. (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1817 May-1817 Dec. (Box 15, Folder 8)
- Box 16- Rufus King Correspondence
  - Notes on Navigation Act, 1818 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, [1818] (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1818 Jan.-1818 Feb. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1818 Mar.-1818 Apr. (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1818 May-1818 Aug. (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1818 Sept.-1818 Oct. (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1818 Nov.-1818 Dec. (Box 16, Folder 7)
- Box 17- Rufus King Correspondence
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, [1819] (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1819 Jan. (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1819 Feb. (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1819 Mar.-1819 May (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1819 June-1819 Oct. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1819 Nov.-1819 Dec. (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Box 18- Rufus King Correspondence, This box includes materials from the box previously labeled 18A.
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, [1820] (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1820 Jan. (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1820 Feb. (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1820 Mar. (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1820 Apr. (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1820 May (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1820 June-1820 Oct. (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1820 Nov. (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1820 Dec. (Box 18, Folder 9)
- Box 19- Rufus King Correspondence
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, [1821] (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1821 Jan. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1821 Feb.-1821 Mar. (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1821 Apr.-1821 Sept. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1821 Oct. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1821 Nov.-1821 Dec. (Box 19, Folder 6)
- Box 20- Rufus King Correspondence
  - Various Notes, [1822] (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1822 Jan. (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1822 Feb.-1822 Mar. (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1822 Apr.-1822 June (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1822 July-1822 Oct. (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1822 Nov.-1822 Dec. (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Various Notes, [1823] (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1823 Jan. (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1823 Feb.-1823 Mar. (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1823 Apr.-1823 June (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1823 July-1823 Oct. (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1823 Nov.-1823 Dec. (Box 20, Folder 12)
- Box 21- Rufus King Correspondence
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1824 Jan.-1824 Feb. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1824 Mar. (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1824 Apr. (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1824 May-1824 June (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1824 July-1824 Dec. (Box 21, Folder 5)
- Box 22- Rufus King Correspondence, This box includes materials from the box previously labelled 22A.
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, [1825] (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1825 Jan.-1825 Feb. (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1825 Mar.-1825 Apr. (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1825 May (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1825 June-1825 July (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1825 Aug.-1825 Sept. (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1825 Oct. (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1825 Nov.-1825 Dec. (Box 22, Folder 8)
- Box 23- Rufus King Correspondence
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, [1826] (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1826 Jan.-1826 Apr. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1826 May (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1826 June-1826 July (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, 1826 Aug.-1826 Oct. (Box 23, Folder 5)
- Box 24- Richard King Materials, Many letters that were in boxes labeled 24, 26, 27 were interfiled chronologically with the correspondence in boxes 1-23. Some material in this box was rehoused from a box entitled "Box A." The box includes material related to Richard King as well as Charles King and John A. King. The Richard King material has been microfilmed on Miscellaneous Microfilm Reel #12.
  - Richard King, Testimony relating to the Riot of 1766 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Richard King, Petitions relating to the Riot of 1766, 1766-1774 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Richard King, Depositions relating to the Riot of 1766 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Richard King, Petitions on behalf of Scarborough, Maine; Poems; Obituary; Inventory of Estate; Genealogy; Other Correspondence, 1766-1852 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Letters to and from John A. King and Charles King, 1835-1893 (Box 24, Folder 5)
- Volume 25- Letterbook
  - Letterbook of letters to Rufus King, 1796-1803 (Volume 28)
- Box 26- Francisco de Miranda Correspondence, Francisco de Miranda material has been microfilmed on Miscellaneous Microfilm Reel #81. Some material in this box was rehoused from a box entitled "Box A." A short calendar of the letters is included in the beginning of the box.
  - Letters to and from Francisco de Miranda, undated (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Letters to and from Francisco de Miranda, 1792-1799 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Letters to and from Francisco de Miranda, 1800-1802 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Letters to and from Francisco de Miranda, 1803-1804 (Box 26, Folder 4)